Finding Aid for the Lisa See Papers LSC.0564
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Exhibition files
  - Exhibition- On Gold Mountain, 9 May 2000-19 Jun 2000 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Transcripts of video for "On Gold Mountain" exhibition at the Autry Museum of Western Heritage; transcript of Angel Island interrogation. Includes two art catalogs for Li-lan; business card of Diane Tepfer, curator of Art in Embassies Program.
  - Autry Parties, 30 May 2000-28 Jul 2000 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Correspondence, guest lists, and invitations relating to opening reception for the "On Gold Mountain" exhibition at the Autry Museum of Western Heritage.
  - Article- CCCLA Yearbook, Jan 2001 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    "On Gold Mountain - A Chinese American Experience Exhibit Travels to the Smithsonian" in the Chinese Chamber of Commerce of Los Angeles yearbook (p. 22).
  - Exhibition- On Gold Mountain, 24 Feb 1997-19 Apr 2000 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Correspondence, exhibition costs, gallery descriptions and floor plans relating to the "On Gold Mountain" exhibit at the Autry Museum of Western Heritage.
  - Autry Children's Gallery, 1999-2001 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    Drafts, correspondence, floorplans, and other materials related to the curation of the On Gold Mountain exhibit.
  - On Gold Mountain Autry correspondence, 2000-2001 (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - On Gold Mountain Autry marketing and public relations (Box 95, Folder 5-6)
  - On Gold Mountain Autry grants, 1999 (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - On Gold Mountain Autry book proposal (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - On Gold Mountain exhibit publicity, 2000-2001 (Box 96, Folder 2-3)
  - On Gold Mountain Autry Family Discovery Gallery opening, 2001 (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Autry comments, 2000-2001 (Box 96, Folder 5-6)
  - On Gold Mountain traveling exhibit prospectus, 2001 (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - Curatorial Assistance, 2001 (Box 96, Folder 8)
    ArtExhibitions publication.
  - Autry-Smithsonian Planning, Correspondence, and Fundraising, 2000-2001 (Box 96, Folder 9-10)
  - Smithsonian opening invitations, 2001 (Box 96, Folder 11)
  - Autry loans lists, 2000-2002 (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - On Gold Mountain fundraising for Smithsonian, 2000-2001 (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - Smithsonian objects lists (Box 97, Folder 6-7)
  - Smithsonian opening mailing list, 2001 (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - Smithsonian comments, 2001 July 15 - August 30 (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - Smithsonian comments, 2001 August 31 - September (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - Smithsonian comments with addresses, 2001 (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - Smithsonian comments without addresses, 2001 (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - Pacific Asia Museum Nominating Committee, 2002 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    Meeting notes, nominating guidelines, trustee responsibilities, roster, and nominating committee notes.
  - Pacific Asia Museum Board notes and records, 2001-2003 (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - Tyrus Wong exhibition comments (Box 98, Folder 8)
  - Tyrus Wong exhibition comments, circa 2004 (Box 99, Folder 1-2)
- Personal files
  This series includes appointment books; personal notebooks with notes related to appointments, her personal life, and ideas; and materials related to See's undergraduate career including coursework and notes.
  - Loyola Marymount University, 26 May 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Program and order of exercises for 67th annual commencement.
  - Miss L.A. Chinatown Pageant, 27 Jan 2001 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    32nd Annual Pageant Program for "Miss Los Angeles Chinatown" in which Lisa See participated as a judge.
  - Old Loyola Stuff, 1977-1979 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Papers written for Loyola Marymount University courses CA 420 and HS 406; grades; notes. Also includes general incoming correspondence.
  - Course Work for LMU (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Notebook and worksheets for Greek language course at Loyola Marymount University.
  - Course Work for LMU, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Notebook, exams and notes for course HS 406, "Hellenistic Civilization", at Loyola Marymount University.
  - Bachelor of Arts Degree, 26 May 1979 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Lisa See's Bachelor of Arts Degree from the College of Liberal Arts at Loyola Marymount University.
  - Calendars; Notes, 1980-1983 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Handmade calendars with writings at the bottom and colored stars and dots placed on particular days; notes. Also includes memo to Nancy Perlman relating to "Lotus Land"; Publisher's Weekly dated 25 October 1985 (Lisa See is listed in masthead).
  - Appointment Book, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    Spiral-bound appointment book.
  - Loyola Marymount University, 1979-1980 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    Notebook containing course work for at least two classes, one on Greek language, one on Mexican culture/history (CO 398).
  - Loyola Marymount University, 1976-1978 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    Notebook containing course work for Greek language class.
  - Loyola Marymount University, 1982; 1983 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    Two issues of Loyola Marymount University's "Vistas" magazines (v. 6, no. 1 and v. 7, no. 1). Photographs of Carolyn See on page 25 in both volumes.
  - 1991 Calendar, Nov 1990 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    Calendar entitled "1991 Denver Water Department Calendar of Edible Xeriscape". The month of October has many days associated with differently colored hand-drawn stars.
  - Notebooks (Box 43, Folder 9)
    Two spiral-bound notebooks containing notes, telephone numbers, lists, etc. One book contains loose items.
  - Notebooks (Box 43, Folder 10)
    Two spiral-bound notebooks containing notes, telephone numbers, lists, etc. One notebook contains loose items; the other notebook has "ARTICLES FOR WOMEN'S PAGE IDEAS" written on the front cover.
  - Notebooks (Box 43, Folder 11)
    Two spiral-bound notebooks containing notes, telephone numbers, lists, etc. Both notebooks contain loose items.
  - Notebooks (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Appointment Books, 1983; 1984 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    Two spiral-bound appointment books.
  - Appointment Book; Address Book, 1996; undated (Box 44, Folder 2)
    Spiral-bound appointment book and spiral-bound address and telephone book.
  - Appointment Books, 1991; 1999 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Appointment Books, 1992; 1993 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    Two spiral-bound appointment books. Both books contain loose items.
  - Appointment Books, 1985; 1986 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    Two spiral-bound appointment books. The 1986 book contains loose items.
  - Appointment Books, 1980; 1981 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    Two spiral-bound appointment books with red covers. The 1980 book contains loose items.
  - Appointment Book; Address Book, 1979; undated (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Appointment Books, 1982; 1988 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    Two spiral-bound appointment books. The 1982 book contains loose items.
  - Appointment Books, 1995; 1997 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Appointment Book; Address Book, 1998 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    Appointment and Telephone/Address books within a lavender suede cover. The Telephone/Address book contains loose items.
  - Appointment Book, 2000 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Notepad (Box 45, Folder 6)
    Notepad inside tan suede cover which also contains a business card for Ryukyu Enterprises, a Valentine's Day card from Roy, and an envelope with notes written on it.
  - Address Book (Box 45, Folder 7)
    Address book with dark green cover.
  - WRITER'S SERIES (Box 50, Folder 4)
    Headings for typewritten lists are "WRITERS", "POSSIBLE TOPICS", "POSSIBLE ON-GOING SEGMENTS"; other handwritten lists; notes.
  - Notebooks (Box 53, Folder 7)
    Two 9 1/2" x 6" spiral-bound notebooks containing handwritten notes, in addition to some appointments, addresses and telephone numbers.
  - Notebooks (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - "Writing Waves", 1993-1994 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    "Writing Waves" from Crossroads Elementary School. Contains short essays by Alexander Kendall and Chris Kendall.
  - Bill of Goods (Box 54, Folder 8)
    Handwritten notes.
  - Notebooks, 1985 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Notebooks, circa 1992, undated (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Notebooks, 1995; undated (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Notebook, circa 1984 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    One 9 1/2" x 6" spiral-bound notebooks containing handwritten notes, in addition to some appointments, addresses and telephone numbers.
  - LMU-"Writing for Your Life", 1980-1983 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    Writers conference at Loyola Marymount University organized by Carolyn See. "Monica Highland" is present at the 1983 conference.
  - LMU-"Writing for Your Life", 1979-1984 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    Material relating to Loyola Marymount University writers conference, including brochures, advertisements, announcements, reviews, conference committee meeting minutes, budgets, correspondence, and various lists.
  - Loyola Stuff/Rita, 1978 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    Coursework, evaluations, grade report, and notes for various classes taken at Loyola Marymount University.
  - Course Work-"The 20th Century", 1979 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    Handwritten and typewritten drafts, notes, point outline and screenplay of "The 20th Century" for an independent study course.
  - LMU-"Writing for Your Life", 1979-1980 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    Advertisements, announcements, reviews, media appearances, photographs, and correspondence relating to conference at Loyola Marymount University entitled "Writing for Your Life: A Celebration of California Writers".
  - Writers Conference P.R. 1980, 1979-1980 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    Advertisements, announcements, reviews, various lists, correspondence, brochure, etc., relating to conference at Loyola Marymount University entitled "Writing for Your Life: A Celebration of California Writers".
  - Grade Reports, Restricted material. (Box 65, Folder 2)
    Grade reports from Loyola Marymount University.
  - Grade Transcripts, 1978; Restricted material. (Box 65, Folder 4)
    Transcripts of grades from Loyola Marymount University.
  - Loyola Marymount University, 1980 June 24 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Santa Barbara News-Press.
  - Appointment books, 1994, 2001-2010 (Box 99, Folder 5)
    Eleven appointment books.
- Awards and memorabilia
  This series includes certificates, plaques, and a statuette with which See was honored.
  - Awards (Box 99, Folder 3-4)
    This includes awards from the Chinese American Librarians Association, the Office of the Governor of the State of Nevada, Metro Magazine, and others.
  - Awards, 2001 (Box 100)
    This contains a statuette eagle Distinguished Citizen award from the San Gabriel County Valley Council BSA.
  - Awards (Box 101)
    This includes framed or mounted awards from Pennsylvania State University, the Aerospace Asian American Association, the Asian/Pacific American Librarians Association (APALA), and the California Book Awards. It also includes plaques from the University of Nebraska Omah (UNO) a for being a keynote speaker for the UNO Women of Color Awards and from another university for participating in their annual Distinguished Lecture series.
  - Awards, 2001, 2003-2004, 2006-2007, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    This consists of thirteen awards and certificates of recognition from organizations such as the Alhambra School District, Los Angeles Public Library, United States Congress and Senate, the California State Board of Equalization, the California State Senate and Assembly, and the California State Controller.
  - Poster, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    This poster from the 75th Anniversary California Book Awards commemorates the winners, which includes a silver medal in fiction for Snow Flower and the Secret Fan.